NAUSHAD RUPAKAR

- naushad.rupakar@yahoo.com
- 88491148819925462585

- □ https://www.linkedin.com/in/naushad-rupakar-77a945213
- □ Address : "Aashray"

Bungalow no-835, Someshwar society,

Sector-27, Gandhinagar, Gujarat-382027, INDIA

OBJECTIVE AND EXPERIENCE SCREENSHOT

With 12+Years of rich hand Experience in end-to-end support function,

I would hold a key position in support function management in order to contribute to the organization's growth by defining & deploying technical, operational and organizational strategies.

Managing supportoperations towards improvement of system process and operational excellence to achieve the profitable goals with my experience snap shot as below.

Service Design, Service Process defining and its role out.

Risk analysis and its mitigation/provisioning.

Spare planning for field calls, Management of warehouses with adequate stocking and avoidance of NMI and unwanted logistic movements.

Field service operation for call closure, revenue and customer satisfaction.

Man power planning according to call load, their skill and performance tracking and upgrade

Vendor management for service performance review against SLA, MSL and servicerevenue and their service payouts.

Product failure analysis and advocacy for its prevention and corrective action with the helpof quality and R&D.

Business process automation and optimization on CRM/Web portal for its best efficiency accuracy and controls

EXPERIENCE

Oct 2022 to present

Jan 2019 -Sept 2022 Reliance Jio infocomm Itd Depury Manager, Ahmedabad

Responsibilities:

- Drive home connect and care operations in the assigned territory
- Source and train technicians by tieing up with target colleges
- Conduct classroom and on the job trainings for technicians
- Mentor and guide technicians to enhance productivity
- Ensure zero defect execution of home connect activity
- Drive home connect installation and fault repair related SLA
- Ensure customer satisfaction
- Ensure adherence to processes as per company defined SLAs
- Team Management, Team Building

Feb 2016 – Jan2019

ONSITEGO ELECTROSERVICES PRIVATE LIMITED (MUMBAI)

Escalation Manager

Responsible for managing Gujarat TATA croma and Vijay sales stores Escalations management process. Managing escalations calls through various sources-CEO/social media/sales channel/stores etc.

Helping to manage process for an entire above organization, managing a team of customer service staff & Stores Operational staff, communicating courteously with customers by telephone, email, and letter and face to face, investigating and solving customer's problems, which may be complex or long-standing problem or consumer cases problem.

Doing root cause analysis of customer complaints, prepare corrective and preventive action, analyzing statistics or other data to determine the level of customer service is providing by the after sales team meeting with other departments (sales, marketing, product quality and supplier) to discuss possible improvement on the product quality and customer service improvement.

Monitoring service delivery, Support to service provider & sales network, Implementing process & system. Customer satisfaction score, Dealers/distributors/customer's visits. planning for spare/accessories for branch & ASP's.

Aug 2012 - April 2016

B2X India service solutions pvt. Ltd(Mumbai) (Google Pixel)

Virtual center manager (Gujarat, Rajasthan, MP)

Selected, appointed, developed & managed franchise & franchisee setup & operation, monitoring of franchise performance and providing support for development of products for greater marketpenetration and to achieve targeted revenue,

Overall CSD Administration & and Cost Control

Review of franchise's performance, providing feedback and suggesting strategy for development,

Conducting review meetings with sales service partners,

spare parts distributors, conducting trade satisfaction survey achieving business excellence,

Conducting training for after sales service executives / technicians and trade partner's manpower,

Arranging timely supply of spares to franchise, inventory management and accounting,

Cost control and cost optimization by monitoring high value spares,

MIS preparation and circulation to management,

Coordination with Branch / HO and attending review meetings,

Control Defective Stock Generation& sure effective disposal. Material Management.

Samsung Authorized Service Centre Manager, N.K. Enterprise, Gandhinagar/ Mehsana.

Supervi o n o f S e r c e C e n e r o f h е R е g i 0 n E n s u n g o n s i t e T A T n 4 8 H s E n s u n g Е ngineer Productivity >=8acrossState.Ensuring Customer Satisfaction. Implementing processes for revenue leakage prevention. Ensuring TAT Parameters of Service Centre operations. Ensuring Bounce Rate with 10% limit.

EDUCATION

- DIPLOMA IN ELECTRICAL(NCVT) from Advance Training Institute, under DGE&T, Govt. of India, Ministry of Labor in year 1992, awarded 1st Class and secured 68% marks. (Two years Course) (2004)
- Completed All India Trade Test for National Apprenticeship Trade Examination in trade under the Apprenticeship Act-1961(2007)
- Certificate in consumer protection in year 2006, from Indira Gandhi National Open University, awarded 2nd division and secured 56% marks.
- Gujarat state higher education board Std-12(Commerce) secured 47% marks (2002).
- Gujarat state education board Std-10 secured 77% marks (2000).

SKILLS

- Problem solving
- Team building
- **Decision making**
- · MS office with advanced excel
- Corporate communication
- Proficiency in Generating
- ReportsMail
- · Implementation on MOM
- Sympathy
- Group Meetings
- Floor manage with follow the covid 19 guidelines
- · Well versed with technology and application of internet
- . Data analysis
- Good Communication Skills

PROJECTS

Quick Care Quality and Progressive

Service provide to the customer for mobile phones with following criterias of the KPI along with manage all the service operations.

· Pick and drop service

Pick and drop service provided to the customer only on 199 and 99 only for drops through collaboration with uber and through the local office staff also.

· Sale secure and protection plan

Sale secure and protection plan for the mobile phones to the customer under multiple criteria with multiple price through the collaboration with servify portal.

. Loyalty coupon to increase the sale

Loyalty coupon issued to the customer to increase the sales of the Samsung product through the provided application by the company along with raise a query for the same on the Samsung service portal.

Lakshya

Zero dissatisfaction

Zero abnormalities

INTERESTS

- Surfing internet,Listen music
- Watch movies
- Learn from youtube and google

LANGUAGES

English,Hindi,Gujarat

٠

STRENGTHS

- Ability to work as a Team-member.
- Convincing Power.
- Prompt Accept to changes of System.
- Good Communication Skills.
- Sound Understanding of working of the business process at different levels.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth : 01/10/1984
Marital Status : Married
Nationality : INDIAN

• Permanent address: Aashray, Bungalow no-835, someshwar society, sector-27, Gandhinagar, Gujarat, INDIA

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.

Date : Place :

NAUSHAD RUPAKAR